

### Profile

Full stack software engineer that specializes in JavaScript and PHP. I strive to make software easier to use and manage through good design, clean code, and effective communication. I love to automate things and server-side tasks to build and deploy at scale.

# Employment History

Software Engineer at Field Nation, Minneapolis, Minnesota, USA May 2022 — Present

- Developing vetting and matching features in the platform for Skills clients.
- Working on a highly available distributed SaaS platform.
- Deployed multiple services on stage.

## Software Engineer at ShareTrip, Dhaka, Bangladesh

September 2018 — May 2022

- Implemented Flight and Hotel admin panel for sales and marketing team.
- Managed Analytical report for backend and ticket provider automation and visa management.
- Written API for hotel management with full featured backend for hotel management team to check availability.
- Built and designed highly available distributed AdTech platform.
- Managed thousands of requests per second on queue based microservice and developed a client panel for managing property, campaign and ads.

# Junior Software Engineer at Ticket Chai Ltd, Dhaka, Bangladesh October 2017 — August 2018

- Written API for Search and detailed information and added business logic.
- Developed an admin panel for managing flights for the sales team, which helped them to support customers effectively.
- Developed an event management solution for the event management team.

## Education

Post Graduate Diploma in Information Technology, Jahangirnagar University, Savar, Dhaka, Bangladesh

September 2018 — January 2020

# ➤ Extra-curricular activities

Volunteer at Welcome Club BD, Dhaka

2016 - 2018

#### **Contact Info**

Kawla, Airport Dhaka, 1229 Bangladesh +8801723458494

habibur.rahman.rawnak@gmail.com

#### Links

linkedin.com/in/hbrawnak github.com/hbrawnak Personal Site (habib.im)

### **Skills**

**JavaScript** 

**TypeScript** 

Node.js

React

ES<sub>6</sub>

PHP

MySQL

PostgreSQL

NoSQL

Redis

API

Docker

**Kubernetes** 

**AWS** 

Agile and Scrum

#### Languages

English

Bengali

#### **Hobbies**

Football, Travel and Bicycling